SCOTT SILVER

Software Developer

CONTACT ME!

(615)-974-6679

scottsilver47@gmail.com

In linkedin.com/in/scottsilver47/

github.com/Scott47

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a learner and developer with a zeal for persevering through challenging problems. Past experience working with data lead to my pursuit of software development. I am currently learning and working with JavaScript, React, Python, Django and SQL.

PROJECTS

XC STATS

FULL STACK CAPSTONE *github.com/Scott47*

XC Stats is a full stack Django/React app that allows high school cross country coaches to manage runner, team, and event information. Coaches can build and edit rosters, track runner contact information, meet times, runner pace, personal records on a specific course, etc.

OUR STORY MAPS FRONT-END CAPSTONE

github.com/Scott47

Our Story Maps is a single page application using React.JS and ArcGIS API. It is intended for users to create immersive stories about place combining text, interactive maps ,and other multimedia context. The app demonstrates full CRUD functionality. User data and story elements were stored using JSON-server.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA-BIRMINGHAM (UAB)

B.A. Anthropology

UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA-BIRMINGHAM (UAB)

33 credit hours toward M.A. Anthropology.

COMMUNITY

- PyTN2020 Volunteer
- Code For Nashville COVID-19 response volunteer
- Teaching assistant, NSS mini-bootcamp, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery
- Contributor for Underground.js using React, CSS, & Bootstrap

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

- Hands on application of Object Oriented Programming fundamentals through group and individual projects in a simulated agile, mockcompany environment
- Front-end development using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React, third-party APIs
- Server-side development with Python/Django, Django REST Framework, including SQL and building ERDs (Entity Relationship Diagrams).
- Source code version control with git/GitHub
- · Built a full stack application with Django & React
- Built a single page application with React and ArcGIS API for developers

TEACHER, MATH CONTENT CHAIR

2013 - 2019

- Collected and analyzed student data to plan and execute daily lesson plans.
- Utilized Microsoft Excel, Kickboard, LiveSchool, and Illuminate Education software to input, sort, and analyze student data to inform daily instruction, develop growth mindsets and create a positive learning culture.
- Worked collaboratively with content and grade level teams.
- Daily contact with parents and community stakeholders.
- Designed and executed professional development for teachers.
- Lead and facilitated professional learning community of math teachers from 5th through 8th grade
- Served on school leadership team and strategic school design team.

PROGRAM COORDINATOR/FARM TO SCHOOL JONES VALLEY TEACHING FARM

2009 - 2012

- Researched and collected data to successfully advocate for wellness policies for school food improvement in Jefferson County Schools.
- Researched and collected data from grant application, renewal, and reporting.
- Organized and conducted professional development workshops for teachers and child nutrition workers.
- Developed Good School Food program by investing community stakeholders for future implementation of school gardens, farmer's markets and healthy food education

INTERNSHIP, RESEARCH TEAM LEAD, NASA DEVELOP PROGRAM, UAB

2008 - 2009

- Developed West Nile Virus risk model for Auburn, AL by investigating environmental factors and collected mosquito data using geospatial ArcGIS and processed ASTER and Landsat imagery.
- Managed a team of 8 student researchers